rlcdn.com 2009-11-08

# Social Networking Data Append, Reverse Email Lookup - Rapleaf

### Rapleaf Spruce Product Privacy Statement

Rapleaf is the leader in automated search for people information on the social web. Our solutions help businesses plan online media, gain customer insight, and manage fraud risk. Rapleaf Spruce is a new product that enables advertisers to reach targeted audiences based on Rapleaf data.

We believe in the power of transparency, choice, and control when it comes to personal information online. We view privacy and security as fundamental design requirements in our technologies and services and core to our business practices and operations. The purpose of this privacy statement is to help our clients, partners and members of the public understand how the Rapleaf Spruce product works, and the measures we have taken to protect the privacy of the information we hold.

**What data does Rapleaf collect?**

Rapleaf collects personal information and stores it in the "Rapleaf Database." Rapleaf data is structured around individual email addresses and contains personally and non-personally identifiable information. We obtain this information from a variety of sources. Our proprietary technology collects information from the Internet that users have chosen to make public. In other words, this means the information we collect is the same information anyone could find on one of the major search engines. What we do is aggregate it into an easy to read report. We also obtain data from other information providers that we use to augment the information we collect.

For more information on Rapleaf data see our Rapleaf Data Privacy Statement.

**How does Rapleaf Spruce work?**

Rapleaf Spruce allows websites and advertisers to customize content for users based on Rapleaf data. When a user visits one of our partner sites, our partner sends us an encrypted unique identifier that allows us to search the Rapleaf database to determine whether that user is in our database. If there is a match, we will directly or through our partners drop anonymous cookies that provide an aggregate profile of the user.

**Does Rapleaf Spruce provide personally identifiable information?**

No. Rapleaf only provides segmentation information such as demographics, interests or online habits. This allows advertisers to tailor their offerings and improve user experience on the web. 

**Does Rapleaf Spruce collect information about users' web use?**

Once a Rapleaf cookie is dropped onto a user’s machine, it does not collect any data about the users web use and it cannot be traced back to any personally identifiable information about the user. It is completely anonymous.

**How serious is Rapleaf about privacy and security?**

Protecting privacy is our top priority at Rapleaf. We comply with all applicable privacy laws and regulations about managing our database. Our Rapleaf Privacy Statement governs information collected on the Rapleaf domains. We use industry standard security measures to make sure the information in our databases is secure. And before any transfer of data, we align our privacy policies and practices with our business customers.

**How serious is Rapleaf about transparency, choice and control?**

We believe that transparency and user choice are essential to user privacy on the internet. We allow users to access and edit much of the information we know about them. Register for our service to discover what information about you is available online and to edit your Internet footprint. And if you’d prefer not to be a part of our program, you can opt out of the Rapleaf database at any time. Simply click here and you will be permanently removed from our database. It is really that simple.

**How long do Rapleaf Spruce cookies last?**

Rapleaf Spruce cookies expire 90 days after they are set. Third-party cookies may have different expiration dates.

If you have any questions, please contact us at [privacy@rapleaf.com](mailto:privacy@rapleaf.com).
